# **Emirhan Kaplan**

emskaplann@gmail.com | (929)-405-8405 | New York City, NY Personal Website | LinkedIn | GitHub | Medium | Behance

# **Full-Stack Web Developer**

Full-Stack Web and Cross-Platform Mobile App Developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript. I have a passion for coding since sixth grade, and creating apps from scratch makes me excited about software-engineering. I would love being part of companies with creative cultures, and I am looking forward to contributing my full capacity and experience.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, React Native, JWT, IBM Watson, Twitter API, Stripe, PostgreSQL, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, jQuery, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI, Semantic-UI React, React-Bootstrap, Native-Base

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Forever 31 - Github Front-End | Github Back-End | Demo

A clone of Forever 21 Store that has a much simpler and user-friendly design than the original one.

- Combined, React, Redux, React Semantic-UI and <u>Popmotion</u>(Pose) to design front-end architecture and behaviors.
- Integrated IBM Watson to present an AI that helps the user navigate between pages and sort products.
- Employed Stripe to manage user payments and increase security measures for personal information.
- Programmed Back-End with Ruby on Rails to build an API that serves multiple front-end clients.

#### ToDo App - Github Front-End | Github Back-End | Github Mobile | Demo

A project management tool that allows students to track the progress and completion of their projects.

- Designed web appearance with React-Bootstrap that generated a mobile-first approach.
- Merged reusable React components to React Native, saving time in project completion.
- Implemented JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information.

### Word-Tetris - Github Front-End | Github Back-End | Github Mobile | Demo

A game that helps individuals to improve their typing skills.

- Used Vanilla JavaScript to create an interactive SPA.
- Incorporated News API, producing fresh words at every new game.
- Operated AsyncStorage in the mobile app to save the user's credentials on each device.

#### ArtBot - Github | Website | Twitter

A bot that tweets historical paintings from WikiArt's most viewed category four times in a day.

- Programmed in Ruby provided a server-side application.
- Deployed on Heroku stored Images temporarily enough to posting tweets.
- Combined Twitter API with WikiArt API produced unique images for each post.
- Utilized Clockwork Gem resulted in a server that runs jobs automatically by itself in the background.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Server, Cappy Food Corp., Staten Island, NY

September 2019 - Present

- Ensured optimal guest experience by seating guests, taking orders, serving dishes and removing dinnerware promptly and with a positive attitude.
- Negotiated and resolved customer concerns.
- Consistently achieved above 20% charge tip percentage, demonstrating skills providing quality customer service.

# Apprentice Optician, Berrak Optical Shop, Istanbul, Turkey

May 2018 - September 2018

- Arranged and maintained displays of optical merchandise.
- Assisted clients in selecting frames according to style and color, and ensured that frames are coordinated with facial and eye measurements and optical prescriptions.
- Heated, shaped or bent plastic or metal frames to adjust eyeglasses to fit clients, using tools and hands.

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School, New York, U.S.

September 2019 - December 2019

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript curriculum.